Kenneth C.M. Sills: Administrative Records A01.02.08
George J. Mitchell Department of Special Collections & Archives, Bowdoin College Library, Brunswick, Maine 04011
Kenneth C.M. Sills: administrative records
1889-1969
George J. Mitchell Department of Special Collections & Archives, Bowdoin College Library, Brunswick, Maine 04011
Bowdoin College. Office of the President
A01.02.08
149
47.25 Linear Feet
Biographical/Historical Note
Kenneth Charles Morton Sills (1879-1954) was Bowdoin's eighth president. A graduate in the class of 1901, he served first as Dean of the College (1910-1917) under William DeWitt Hyde. Following Hyde's death in 1917, he served as acting president until 1918 when he assumed the presidency. His tenure in office is the longest in Bowdoin's history, 35 years.
A number of important issues and events characterized his presidency. He served through three wars and the Great Depression, took steps to maintain Bowdoin as a small liberal arts college, fought for and achieved institutional control over athletics, ended the B.S. degree distinction and closed the Medical School of Maine, while strengthening other areas of the curriculum and the faculty.
Scope and Content
Files of President Kenneth C.M. Sills include general office correspondence and specific correspondence relating to the closing of the Medical School of Maine, the conferring of honorary degrees, athletics, fraternities, the Institute of Modern Literature, the establishment of the Kent Island Station, the Tallman Foundation and the Committee on the Limitation of Numbers. The files also include correspondence with a number of prominent alumni including Percival Baxter '98, William W. Lawrence '98, Ripley Dana '01, Harvey D. Gibson '02, Clement Robinson '03, Robert Hale '10, and Robert P.T. Coffin '15. For related Kenneth C.M. Sills materials, see the Kenneth C.M. Sills Collection.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
- Reports of the President, 1891-1952, A01.02.08.01; 42183; 39 Volumes
  Series Description:
  This series contains annual reports of the President of Bowdoin College. From 1905 through 1976, these reports are part of the run of presidents' reports published as issues of the Bowdoin College Bulletin, and are shelved chronologically with the Bulletins. Content of the reports varies, but generally includes a review of the year, changes in faculty and curriculum, issues facing the College, and future needs of the College. A report from the Librarian is included in many of the issues, as is a report from the Dean of the College and the Director of the Museum of Art.
  Arrangement:
  Arranged chronologically.
  Access Restrictions:
  No restrictions.
  - Index to the President's Reports, 1891-1947, 42268 (Volume 1)
  - Index to the President's Reports, 1891-1957 [located in 1.2.9.1], 42269 (Volume 2)
  - #81 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1917-1918, 42270 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #92 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1918-1919, 42271 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #102 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1919-1920, 42272 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #111 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1920-1921, 42273 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #120 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1921-1922, 42274 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #128 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1922-1923, 42275 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #135 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1923-1924, 42276 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #143 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1924-1925, 42277 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #155 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1925-1926, 42278 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #166 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1926-1927, 42279 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #175 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1927-1928, 42280 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #182 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1928-1929, 42281 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #188 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1929-1930, 42282 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #197 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1930-1931, 42283 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #204 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1931-1932, 42284 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #210 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1932-1933, 42285 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #219 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1933-1934, 42286 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #226 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1934-1935, 42287 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #231 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1935-1936, 42288 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #237 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1936-1937, 42289 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #242 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1937-1938, 42290 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #248 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1938-1939, 42291 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #253 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1939-1940, 42292 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #257 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1940-1941, 42293 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #263 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1941-1942, 42294 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #267 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1942-1943, 42295 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #270 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1943-1944, 42296 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #276 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1944-1945, 42297 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #281 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1945-1946, 42298 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #286 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1946-1947, 42299 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #289 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1947-1948, 42300 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #292 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1948-1949, 42301 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #297 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1949-1950, 42302 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #301, Part 1 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1950-1951, 42303 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - #305 Report of the President of Bowdoin College for the Academic Year 1951-1952, 42304 (Bulletin 6.2)
- Addresses, 1918-1952, undated, A01.02.08.02; 42184; 7 Linear Feet
  This series contains baccalaureate addresses from June 16, 1918, to June 1, 1952, inclusive. Occasional addresses and statements made before various groups are also included. The bulk of addresses were made between 1918 and 1952. Included are chapel statements, memorials, opening addresses, and news releases. Some addresses are indexed. Contains both dated and undated files.
  Arranged chronologically by subject.
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: Contents, 42203 (Box 1, Folder 1-16)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "Christian Co-operation" 1918, 42204 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "The Unselfish use of Victory" 1919, 42205 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "A Right Judgment in all Things" 1920, 42206 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "The Virtue of Hope" 1921, 42207 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "The Law of Liberty" 1922, 42208 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "The Responsibility of the Individual" 1923, 42209 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "Idealism in Service" 1924, 42210 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "The Newer Freedom" 1925, 42211 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "The Pursuit of Excellence" 1926, 42212 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "Modern Laodiceans" 1927, 42213 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "Some Attitudes toward Truth" 1928, 42214 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "A Proper Individualism" 1929, 42215 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "The Bases of Loyalty" 1930, 42216 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "Self-discipline, Self-control, Self-respect" 1931, 42217 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1918-1932: "Standing Fast to Liberty" 1932, 42218 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: Contents 1933-1946, 42219 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "The Virtue of Honor" 1933, 42220 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "The Virtue of Courage" 1934, 42221 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "Education for the Common Good" 1935, 42222 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "The Responsibility of Educated Men" 1936, 42223 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "Charity and Democracy" 1937, 42224 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "The Idealistic versus the Realistic View of Life" 1938, 42225 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "A Defense of Democracy" 1939, 42226 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "Renewal of Faith" 1940, 42227 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "The Individual and the State" 1941, 42228 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "Fear not them which kill the body but are not able to kill the soul" 1942, 42229 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: September 12, 1942, 42230 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: January 25, 1943, 42231 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: "Democracy of the Future" May 20, 1943, 42232 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: September 25, 1943, 42233 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: February 5, 1944, 42234 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: May 28, 1944, 42235 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: September 30, 1944, 42236 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: February 3, 1945, 42237 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: May 20, 1945, 42238 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses 1933-1945: October 6, 1945, 42239 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: "Prisoners of Hope" June 21, 1946, 51025 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: September 28, 1946, 51026 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: February 8, 1947, 51027 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: June 1, 1947, 51028 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: September 20, 1947, 51029 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: February 7, 1948, 51030 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: May 30, 1948, 51031 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: September 18, 1948, 51032 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: February 5, 1949, 51033 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: "A Right Judgment in all Things" June 15, 1949, 51034 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: February 4, 1950, 51035 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: June 11, 1950, 51036 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: February 3, 1951, 51037 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: June 10, 1951, 51038 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: September 22, 1951, 51039 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: February 9, 1952, 51040 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Baccalaureate Addresses: June 1, 1952, 51041 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Occasional Addresses index 1919-1940, 51042 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Addresses at Educational Institutions, 51043 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Addresses before various clubs and organizations, 51044 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Acceptance of Gifts, 51045 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Alumni addresses and messages, 51046 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Baccalaureate Addresses, 51047 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Book reviews, 51048 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Bowdoin matters-miscellaneous, 51049 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Bowdoin institutes, 51050 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Addresses at opening of college, 51051 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Memorials and chapel statements - Bowdoin men, 51052 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Newspaper editorials, articles, and statements, 51053 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Radio broadcasts, 51054 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Chapel addresses and statements, 51055 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Worthies of the college, 51056 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Titles of articles and addresses, 51057 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Occasional Addresses index: Chronological arrangement, 51058 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Occasional Addresses 1919-1923, 51059 (Box 3, Folder 18-88)
  - Occasional Addresses 1924-1928 Oct., 51060 (Box 4)
  - Occasional Addresses 1928 Nov.-1930, 51061 (Box 5)
  - Occasional Addresses 1931-1934, 51062 (Box 6)
  - Occasional Addresses 1935-1938 March, 51063 (Box 7)
  - Occasional Addresses 1938 April-1941, 51064 (Box 8)
  - Occasional Addresses 1942-1947, 51065 (Box 9)
  - Occasional Addresses 1948-1952 & Undated, 51066 (Box 10)
  - Occasional Addresses Undated, 51067 (Box 11)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Addresses at educational institutions, 51068 (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Addresses before various clubs and organizations, 51069 (Box 12, Folder 9-40)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Alumni Addresses and messages, 51070 (Box 12, Folder 41-48)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Book reviews, 51071 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Bowdoin events, 51072 (Box 12, Folder 50-62)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Bowdoin institutes, 51073 (Box 12, Folder 63-70)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Chapel Addresses, 51074 (Box 13)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Dictionary of American Biography entries, 51075 (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Media editorials, articles and statements, 51076 (Box 14, Folder 7-15)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Memorials and chapel statements -Bowdoin men, 51077 (Box 14, Folder 16-23)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Opening of the college addresses, 51078 (Box 14, Folder 24-61)
  - Occasional Addresses unindexed: Pre- and Post-presidential addresses, 51079 (Box 14, Folder 62-71)
  - Occasional addresses unindexed: Unidentified addresses, 51080 (Box 14, Folder 72-82)
- Subject Files, 1917-1954, undated, A01.02.08.03; 42185; 12 Linear Feet
  Includes general office, personal and specific correspondence on subjects of ongoing importance to the college. Examples of such subjects include: alumni matters, athletics, faculty and curriculum matters, Committee on the Limitation of Numbers, the Carnegie Corporation, the Medical School, Kent Island and the Tallman Foundation, as well as various other external and internal committees.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - "A Word of Greeting from the President of Bowdoin College," Janurary 1935, 117232 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Freedom and Tenure, 1928-40, 42305 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Athletic Association (Organization of) 1920, 42306 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Day November 3, 1945, 42307 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Fund 1922, 42308 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Matters 1943-50, 42309 (Box 1, Folder 6-11)
  - American Chemical Society 1940-51, 42310 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Foundation 1926-27, 42311 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Mathematical Society 1940-41, 42312 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Anglo-American Hospitality Club, 1920, 42313 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Annual Report of the Director of Athletics April 15, 1942, 42314 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Appropriations 1946-47, 42315 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Association of College Presidents on Athletics 1948-49, 42316 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Athens College (Greece) 1945-46, 42317 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Athletic Department 1929-52 Overflow Folder, 42318 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - Athletics 1926-27, 1942-52, 42319 (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
  - Aviation Course, 42320 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Banks 1933, 42321 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bibliography 1927, 42322 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Birthday Acknowledgements December 1949, 42323 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Boards, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 42324 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Bowdoin After the War" October 1945, 42325 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bowdoin - M.I.T. Degrees 1940-47, 42326 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bowdoin Plan, 1948 Feb, 42327 (Volume 1)
  - Bowdoin Plan, 1949-1950, 42328 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bowdoin Prize 1938, 42329 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bowdoin Prize 1943-45, 42330 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bowdoin Prize 1948, 42331 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bowdoin 10-year plan Conference report 1925, 42332 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bowdoin 10-year plan Correspondence 1926, 42333 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Brunswick Conference on Post-War Planning, 42334 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Brunswick Schools 1922-23, 42335 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Brunswick (School Supt.), 42336 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Budgets and Reports June 1940-41, 42337 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Budget- Department Appropriations 1923-24, 42338 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Burton Bill (Burton-Ball-Hatch-Hill Bill) 1943, 42339 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - By-Laws Changes Committee June 1940, 42340 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cafeteria Committee (App. by Executive Committee 1930), 42341 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - California Trip (San Francisco and Los Angeles) 1949, 42342 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1921-22, 42343 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1933-34, 42344 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chemical Warfare 1941-42, 42345 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chemistry Department 1942, 42346 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Christmas Cards to Men in Service 1942,1943, 1944, 42347 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - C.I.O. 1945, 42348 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Church Matters 1940-41, 50-51, 42349 (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
  - Class of 1876 Proposed Gateway, 42350 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Class of 1901 Reunions 1941, 42351 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Class of 1910 Walk, 42352 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Clement, Percival Wood Prize 1925-51, 42353 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Clippings 1918, 1923-24, 42354 (Box 2, Folder 18, 20)
  - Clippings n.d., 1921-24, 42355 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Clippings n.d., 1925-29, 42356 (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
  - Clippings 1948-49, 42357 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Clippings and Miscellaneous 1931-32, 42358 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - College Entrance Exam Board 1952, 42359 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Columbia - Bowdoin Engineering 1951, 42360 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Commencement (including the Programs) 1908-28, 42361 (Box 2, Folder 28-47)
  - Commencement (including the Programs) 1929-45, 42362 (Box 3, Folder 1-40)
  - Commencement (including the Programs) 1946-1955, 1957, 42363 (Box 4, Folder 1-25)
  - Committee on Art Interests, 42364 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Committee on Blanket Tax, 1930-31, 42365 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Committee on Bowdoin-M.I.T. Plan, 42366 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Committee on Buildings and Grounds August 1926, 42367 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Committee on By-Laws 1934-35, 1941, 42368 (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
  - Committee on Committees, 42369 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Committee on Competitive Scholarships Outside Maine, 42370 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Committee on Completion of 3rd Floor Massachusetts Hall, 42371 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Committee to Consider Pensions and Annuities for the Working Staff of the College, 42372 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Committee on Faculty Salaries (Appointed by the Executive Committee) 1930, 42373 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Committee to Inquire into the Cost of a New Dormitory, 42374 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Committee on Library, 42375 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Committee on Limitation of Numbers, 42376 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Committee on Limitation of Numbers: Alumni Survey Replies, 42377 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Committee on Limitation of Numbers: College Survey Replies, 42378 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Committee on Limitation of Numbers:Correspondence/ Summaries 1923, 42379 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Committee on Limitation of Numbers:Intelligence Tests, 42380 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Committee on Medical Survey, 42381 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Committee on Physical Education, 42382 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Committee on Reading Period, 42383 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Committee on the Relation Between the Directors of the Alumni Fund and the Governing Boards, 42384 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Committee on Revision of the By-Laws, 1945-1947, 42385 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Committee on Student Social Life and Activities, 1948, 42386 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Committees and Boards, 42387 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Committee on Study of Age of Retirement of Faculty Members, 42388 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Committee on the Study of Tuition Costs, 42389 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Committee on Survey of Financial Aspects of Enrollment, 42390 (Box 4, Folder 53-54)
  - Committee on Vacancies 1924-25, 42391 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Committee on Vacancies 1928, 42392 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Committee on Vacancies 1930-31, 42393 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Committee on Weekend Commencement, 42394 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Committee Reports 1936, 42395 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Report to the Visiting Committee of the Governing Boards of Bowdoin College by the Committee to Analyze and Study the Operations of the Department of Physical Education, 42396 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Congratulatory Letters on 20th Anniversary, 42397 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Congress and White House 1917, 42398 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Curtis Prize, 42399 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dana, Ripley - Death, 42400 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Davis Agreement n.d., 42401 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Degrees A.B., B.S. 1941-42, 42402 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Degrees - Out of Course n.d., 1923, 42403 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Diocesan Convention 1937, 42404 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Dole, Frederick 1943-1944, 42405 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Draft, 42406 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Draft Deferment 1950-51, 42407 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dupont 1948-49, 42408 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dyer Trust 1949-52, 42409 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Education Bill 1937, 42410 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Educational Policy Commission (ME) 1947-49, 42411 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Educational Policy Commission (ME) 1949-52, 42412 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Educational Policy Committee (Faculty), 42413 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - English Speaking Union, 42414 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Episcopal Church -- General Synod Montreal 1921, 42415 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Episcopal Church -- Scholarships for Candidates for the Ministry 1921-22, 42416 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - The Episcopal Theological School 1946-1952, 1954, 42417 (Box 5, Folder 24-28)
  - Evans, Harold (Philadelphia), 42418 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Examinations: Armed Forces 1943, 42419 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Examining Committee 1922-1925, 42420 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Examining Committee 1929-31, 1933-52, 42421 (Box 5, Folder 32-54)
  - Executive 5, 42422 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Executive Committee 1921-1925, 42423 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee 1923-1930, 42424 (Box 6, Folder 4-9)
  - Executive Committee 1933-1946, 42425 (Box 6, Folder 10-28)
  - Executive Committee on Surplus Property 1947, 42426 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Executive Committee 1947, 42427 (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
  - Executive Committee 1948-1951, 42428 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Faculty Committee Reports June 1940, 42429 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Exchange - Tuition Project 1947, 42430 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Matters 1951-52, 42431 (Box 7, Folder 8)